A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1997-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1997-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.001
This collection consists of 18,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred on 2000 November 28.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by John Thomas Casteen, the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general records, 1997-1998; seldom-used permanent files, 1971-1998; and, committee files, 1995-1997.
Organization
Series I: General Files, 1997-1998 Boxes 1-40
Series II: Seldom Used Permanent Files, 1971-1998 Boxes 41-51
Series III: Committee Files, 1995-1998 Boxes 51-52
Series IV: Restricted Files, 1997- 1998 Boxes 53-55
Contents List
- Series I: General Files
  - "A-Al" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - "An-Az" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Admissions (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Law (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Medical 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - African-American Affairs 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - African-American Affairs--Woodson Institute (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association--General and Board of Managers (4 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities--General 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education--General (1 of 2) 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education--General (2 of 2) 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education--Leaflets (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Anthropology--General 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions-General A-Z (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Architecture--General 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Art-General 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Art-Arts, Planning and Development (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Art-Bayly Museum 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Asian Studies--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Assessment, Planning and Studies--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Associated Chief Admissions Office of Public Universities--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Associated Western Universities 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Colleges and Universities--General 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Association of Universities (AAU)--General (2 folders) 1997-1998 Jan-Jun (Box 4)
  - Association of Universities (AAU)--General (1 of 3) 1997-1998 Jul-Dec (Box 4)
  - Association of Universities (AAU)--General (2-3 of 3) 1997-1998 Jul-Dec (Box 5)
  - Association of Governing Boards (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Association of Governing Boards--Advisory Council of Presidents (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges--General 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Astronomy--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Athletics--ACC (1 of 2) 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Athletics--ACC (2 of 2) 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--General (3 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--NCAA (1 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--NCAA (2-3 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Attorney General (State)--General 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Auditor--Internal General 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts--General 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - "Ba-Bm" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - "Bn-Br" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - "Bs-Bz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - Birdwood--General 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - Business and Finance--General (1 of 4) 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - Business and Finance--General (2-4 of 4) 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - "Ca-Cn" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 4) 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - "Ca-Cn" Miscellaneous (3-4 of 4) 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - "Co-Cz" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Career Planning and Placement--General 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Casteen, John T. III--General 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Center for Innovative Technology (CIT)--General 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Charlottesville, City of--General 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Charlottesville, City of--Planning and Coordinating Council 1997-1998 (Box 11)
  - Chemistry--General 1997-1998 (Box 11)
  - Classics--General 1997-1998 (Box 11)
  - Clinch Valley College (CVC)--General (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 11)
  - College of Arts and Sciences--General 1997-1998 (Box 11)
  - College Board--General (1-2 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 11)
  - College Board--General (3 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Commerce--General 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia-Century Date Change Initiative Project Office 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Comptroller (State-)-General 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Condolences "A-Z"--General 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Congress--General 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Connie Lee--General 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Continuing Education--General 1997-1998 (Box 13)
  - Council of Presidents--General 1997-1998 (Box 13)
  - "Da-De" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 13)
  - "Df-Dz" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 13)
  - Darden Graduate School of Business Administration--General 1997-1998 (Box 14)
  - Deans' Meetings--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 14)
  - Development (1-4 of 6) 1997-1998 (Box 14)
  - Development (4-6 of 6) 1997-1998 (Box 15)
  - Drama--General 1997-1998 (Box 15)
  - "E" Miscellaneous General 1997-1998 (Box 15)
  - Economics--General 1997-1998 (Box 15)
  - Education--General 1997-1998 (Box 15)
  - Endowment Fund 1997-1998 (Box 15)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--General 1997-1998 (Box 16)
  - English--General (Restricted) 1996-1998 (Box 16)
  - English--General 1997-1998 (Box 16)
  - Enrollment--General 1997-1998 (Box 16)
  - Equal Opportunity Office (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 16)
  - "Fa-Fh" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 16)
  - "Fl-Fz" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 16)
  - "Fl-Fz" Miscellaneous (3 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - Facilities Management--General 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - Faculty--General 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences--General 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - Family Violence Prevention Fund--General 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - Finals--Balcony Collapse (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - Financial Aid to Students--General (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - French Language and Literature--General 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - "Ga-Gn" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - "Go-Gz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - General Assembly--General 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - General Assembly--Legislative Summaries 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - General Counsel--General (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - General Services (State)--General 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - German--General 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - Gifts and Grants "A-C" (1 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - Gifts and Grants "A-C" (2-3 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Gifts and Grants "D-F" (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Gifts and Grants "G-K" (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Gifts and Grants "L-P" (3 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants "Q-S" (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants "T-Z" 1997-1998 (Box 20)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs--General 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governmental and Community Relations 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--General 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--General (Photographs of Governor George Allen and John Casteen) 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office Administration 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Commerce and Trade 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Education 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Finance 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Natural Resources 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Public Safety and Transportation 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Washington Liaison Office (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - "Ha-Hh" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 22)
  - "Hi-Hz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 22)
  - Harrison Foundation--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 22)
  - History General 1997-1998 (Box 22)
  - Honor System--General (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 22)
  - Housing--General 1997-1998 (Box 22)
  - Human Resources (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 22)
  - "I" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) 1997-1998 (Box 22)
  - "I" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1997-1998 (Box 23)
  - Information Technology--State 1997-1998 (Box 23)
  - Information Technology and Communication 1997-1998 (Box 23)
  - International Studies (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 23)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 24)
  - Jefferson, Thomas Memorial Foundation--General 1997-1998 (Box 24)
  - Jefferson Scholars--General 1997-1998 (Box 24)
  - Jefferson Restoration--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 24)
  - "K" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 24)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 24)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (3 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 25)
  - Law--General 1997-1998 (Box 25)
  - Lawn Society 1997-1998 (Box 25)
  - Library--General 1997-1998 (Box 25)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 25)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 25)
  - "Mf-Mz" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 26)
  - Major Events, Office of (3 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 26)
  - Management and Budget--General (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 26)
  - Mariner's Museum--General (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 27)
  - Medical Center--General (3 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 27)
  - Medical Center Hospital--General 1997-1998 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center--Medical School 1997-1998 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center--Nursing School 1997-1998 (Box 28)
  - Miller Center (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 28)
  - Music--General 1997-1998 (Box 28)
  - "N-Na" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 28)
  - "Nb-Nz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 29)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges NASULGC) (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 29)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--Committee on International Affairs 1997-1998 (Box 29)
  - National Science Foundation--General 1997-1998 (Box 29)
  - Nellie Mae (1 of 4) 1997-1998 (Box 29)
  - Nellie Mae (2-4 of 4) 1997-1998 (Box 30)
  - Newcomb Hall--General 1997-1998 (Box 30)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 30)
  - Oak Ridge Associated Universities--General 1997-1998 (Box 30)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 30)
  - "Pa-Ph" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 30)
  - "Pa-Ph" Miscellaneous (3 of 3) 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - "Pl-Pz" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - Parking and Transportation--General (State) (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - Parking and Transportation--General (University) 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - Personnel and Training--General 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - Philosophy--General 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - Physics--General 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - Physics (NEAL)--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - Planning (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - Planning and Budget (State) 1997-1998 (Box 31)
  - Planning and Budget (State)--Medical (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - Planning and Budget (UVA)--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - President's Senior Cabinet Meetings--General 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - Promotions and Tenure--General 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - Provost--General 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - Provost-Vice-Provost for Research--General 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - Psychology 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - "Ra-Rh" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - "Ri-Rz" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - Rector, University of Virginia 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - Real Estate Foundation-General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - Recommendations A-Z 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - Registrar-General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - Religious Studies--General 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - Religious Studies--Heather Warren (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - Research and Public Service (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - Request for Nominations (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - ROTC-General 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - ROTC-Air Force 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - ROTC-Army 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - ROTC-Navy 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - Rotunda Society--General 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - "Sa-Sh" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 33)
  - "Si-Sn" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 34)
  - "So" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 34)
  - "Sp-Sz" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 34)
  - Salaries 1997-1998 (Box 34)
  - Senate-Universities 1997-1998 (Box 34)
  - Slavic Languages and Literature--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 34)
  - Sociology--General 1997-1998 (Box 34)
  - South Africa (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 34)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS)--General (1-2 of 4) 1997-1998 (Box 34)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS)--General (3-4 of 4) 1997-1998 (Box 35)
  - Southern Regional Education Board--General 1997-1998 (Box 35)
  - Spanish, Italian, and Portuguese--General 1997-1998 (Box 35)
  - Sponsored Programs--General 1997-1998 (Box 35)
  - State Council on Higher Education 1997-1998 (Box 35)
  - State Council on Higher Education (SCHEV)--General 1997-1998 (Box 35)
  - State Council on Higher Education (SCHEV)--Council Notes (1 of 2) 1997-1998 (Box 35)
  - State Council on Higher Education (SCHEV)--Council Notes (2 of 2) 1997-1998 (Box 36)
  - State Department of Education 1997-1998 (Box 36)
  - Student Affairs--General 1997-1998 Jan-Jun (Box 36)
  - Student Affairs--General 1997-1998 Jul-Dec (Box 36)
  - Student Affairs--Fraternities/Sororities--General 1997-1998 (Box 36)
  - Student Council--General 1997-1998 (Box 36)
  - Summer Session--General 1997-1998 (Box 36)
  - "Ta-Te" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 36)
  - "Tf-Tz" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 37)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 37)
  - United States Department of Education 1997-1998 (Box 37)
  - United Way--General 1997-1998 (Box 37)
  - Universities Research Association--General 1997-1998 (Box 37)
  - University Guides--General 1997-1998 (Box 37)
  - University Journal--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 37)
  - University of Virginia Foundation--General (3 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 38)
  - University of Virginia Reactor 1997-1998 (Box 38)
  - University Police--General 1997-1998 (Box 38)
  - University Police II--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 38)
  - University Press of Virginia--General 1997-1998 (Box 38)
  - University Relations/Press Office--General 1997-1998 (Box 38)
  - University Union--General 1997-1998 (Box 39)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 39)
  - Virginia Academy of Science--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 39)
  - Virginia Business Higher Education Council (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 39)
  - Virginia Festival of American Film--General 1997-1998 (Box 40)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 40)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation (VSAF)--General (empty) 1997-1998 (Box 40)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 40)
  - "Wi-Wz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 40)
  - Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service--General 1997-1998 (Box 40)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 40)
- Series II: Seldom Used Permanent Files
  - Accuracy in Academia 1985-1986 (Box 41)
  - AIDS (2 folders) 1987-1992 (Box 41)
  - AIDS II 1993-1995 (Box 41)
  - Bell, Jason 1997-1998 (Box 41)
  - Clinch Valley College--Advisory Committee II (1-2 of 3) 1992-1998 (Box 41)
  - Clinch Valley College--Advisory Committee II (3 of 3) 1992-1998 (Box 42)
  - Church, Melinda D. 1993-1995 (Box 42)
  - Craddock, Heather 1995-1997 (Box 42)
  - Development--Capital Campaign III (1-3 of 5) 1994-1996 (Box 42)
  - Development--Capital Campaign III (4-5 of 5) 1994-1996 (Box 43)
  - Endowment Fund--Meeting Agenda-Minutes I (2 folders) 1974-1993 (Box 43)
  - Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action IX (1 of 2) 1993-1995 (Box 43)
  - Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action IX (2 of 2) 1993-1995 (Box 44)
  - Founder's Day II 1993-1996 (Box 44)
  - General Counsel (Restricted) 1989-1998 (Box 44)
  - General Counsel--Goodman, Lee E. 1995-1997 (Box 44)
  - Governor-A.L. Philpott Manufacturing Research (3 folders) 1992-1995 (Box 44)
  - Medical Center--Master Plan II 1981-1983 (Box 45)
  - Medical Center--Organization 1971-1978 (Box 45)
  - Medical Center--Towers II 1984 (Box 45)
  - Memos II (2 folders) 1981-1993 (Box 45)
  - Miller Center IV (1 of 5) 1992-1996 (Box 45)
  - Miller Center IV (2-5 of 5) 1992-1996 (Box 46)
  - National Policy Board/CHEA I (1 of 4) 1995-1996 (Box 46)
  - National Policy Board/CHEA I (2-4 of 4) 1995-1996 (Box 47)
  - National Policy Board/CHEA II (1 of 5) 1996-1997 (Box 47)
  - National Policy Board/CHEA II (2-5 of 5) 1996-1997 (Box 48)
  - Physics (SURA)--Newsletter 1984-1995 (Box 48)
  - Physics (NEAL) (SURA)-Site 1981-1983 (Box 49)
  - South Africa II (3 folders) 1986-1996 (Box 49)
  - University Associates Program II (1 of 3) 1992-1997 (Box 49)
  - University Associates Program II (2-3 of 3) 1992-1997 (Box 50)
  - University Columbarium 1991 Jun (Box 50)
  - Visitors--General (1-3 of 5) 1996 Jul-1997 Jun (Box 50)
  - Visitors--General (4-5 of 5) 1996 Jul-1997 Jun (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Allen, J. Michael 1998 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Birckhead, Franklin K. 1994-1997 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Dalhouse, Warner N. 1992-1997 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Jesse, Evans B. 1990-1997 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--LaLonde, Kristine (student) 1997 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Leon, Arnold H. 1990-1997 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Morie, Elizabeth D. (Mrs.) 1988-1996 (Box 51)
- Series III: University Committees
  - University Committees--General 1995-1996 (Box 51)
  - Athletics Advisory Council 1995-1997 (Box 51)
  - Benefits 1995-1997 (Box 51)
  - Commencement and Convocations 1995-1997 (Box 51)
  - Commencement and Convocations--Processions Subcommittee 1995-1997 (Box 51)
  - Commencement and Convocations--Public Occasions Subcommittee 1995-1997 (Box 51)
  - Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Financial Aid Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Information Technology Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Libraries Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Master Planning Council 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Names 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Radiation Safety Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Rotunda Fire, Commemoration of the 100th Anniversary (empty) 1995-1996 (Box 52)
  - Sexual Assault and Judicial Policy Committee 1995-1998 (Box 52)
  - Undergraduate Admissions Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - University Press of Virginia Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Vice-Presidential Committees 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Virginia Status of University Students Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
  - Women's Concerns Committee 1995-1997 (Box 52)
- Series IV: Restricted Files (Box 53-56)